Guide to the Paul Rapoport Foundation records, circa 1987-2014.
Rapoport, Paul Foundation records
- Series III. Grant Files
  - Senior Action (SAGE): Older Lesbian Project, 1995-1997 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - SAGE: Older Lesbians Project, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - SAGE: Technical Assistance, 1997-1998 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - SAGE: Older Lesbian Project, 1997-1999 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - SAGE: One-time-only grant, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - SAGE, Inc. G.O.E., 1998-1999 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - SAGE g.o.e., 2000 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Senior Action in a Gay Environment G.O.E. (2-year grant), 2001-2003 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - SAGE G.O.E. (2-year-grant), 2003-2004 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Senior Action in a Gay Environment G.O.E., 2005-2006 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - SAGE (Folder #1 of 2): Expansion of Services for Seniors of Color, 2010-2012 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - SAGE (Folder #2 of 2): Expansion of Services for Seniors of Color, 2010-2011 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Servicemembers Legal Defense Network (SLDN) G.O.E., 1997-2006, 2010 (Box 22, Folder 16-21)
  - Sylvia Rivera Law Project, Inc. G.O.E., 2005-2010 (Box 22, Folder 22-24)
  - Sylvia Rivera Law Project, Inc w/ ALF, FIERCE, QEJ: Infrastr. Dvlpmnt./ Shared Communications, 2010-2011, 2014 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Sylvia Rivera Law Project, Inc: Disability Justice Program, 2011-2014 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Support Center TA for NYAC, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Support Center PWA Health Group, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Support Center TA for Identity House, 1999, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Support Center T.A. to GLSEN, Inc., 2000 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Support Center TA to PWA Health Group, 1997-1998 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Tides Foundation: Whole Foods Project (fiscal agent), 1996 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Training Institute for Mental Hlth. Prct.: Services for Generation Q, 2007-2009 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Transgender Legal Defense and Education Fund: Name Change Project, 2007-2009 (Box 23, Folder 8-10)
  - Trinity Evangelical Lutheran Church of Manhattan: Trinity Place, 2008-2009 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - United States Student Assn: NYC LGBT Training, 2004-2006 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Urban Justice Center: Lesbian and Gay Youth Project, 1995-2000 (Box 23, Folder 13-16)
  - Urban Justice Center: PCYP, 2002-2003 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Urban Justice Center: Peter Cicchino Youth Project, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Urban Justice Center: Peter Cicchino Youth Project, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Urban Justice Center as fiscal agent for Sylvia Rivera Law, 2004-2005 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Urban Justice Center: Peter Cicchino Youth Project, 2006-2007 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Visiting Nurse Service: HIV/AIDS Self Care Guide, 1995-1997 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Westchester Jewish Community Services: Center Lane Weekend, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Westchester Jewish Community Services: Center Lane, 1997-1998 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Westchester Jewish Community Services: One-time-only grant, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Westchester Jewish Community Services.: Center Lane, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Westchester Jewish Community Services: Center Lane, 2004-2005 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Westchester Jewish Community Services (WJCS): Center Lane Yonkers Satellite, 2005-2007 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Women's Educational Media: Preventing Homophobia, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Youth Communications G.O.E., 1997-1999 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Youth Communication: "In the System, In the Life", 2003-2005 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Youth Communication G.O.E., 1999-2001 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Youth Communication Service.: Training Initiative, 2000-2002 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - The Paul Rapoport Charitable Trust: Grants 1983, 1983-1984 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - The Paul Rapoport Charitable Trust: Grants 1984, 1984-1985 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - The Paul Rapoport Charitable Trust: Grants 1985, 1985-1993 (Box 24, Folder 1-9)
  - Grants Awarded, Eugene Chen fellowship, 2010-2012, 2014 (Box 24, Folder 10)
- Series IV. Publications
  - A Broken Bargain: Discrimination, Fewer Benefits and More Taxes for LGBT Workers, June 2013 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    from Movement Advancement Project (Full Report, Condensed Version, and Executive Summary)
  - A Broken Bargain for Transgender Workers, A Broken Bargain for LGBT Workers of Color, September-November 2013 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    supplemental reports to A Broken Bargain: Discrimination…for LGBT Workers, also incl. Spanish copy of …Workers of Color
  - Movement Advancement Project (MAP) Standard Annual Reporting, 2007 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - MAP Standard Annual Reporting, 2008 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - MAP: Building LGBT Nonprofit Leadership Talent, November 2009 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - MAP Standard Annual Reporting, 2010 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - MAP Standard Annual Reporting, 2011 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - MAP Standard Annual Reporting, 2012 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - MAP Standard Annual Reporting, 2013 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Resisting Racism: An Action Guide, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    Gerald L. Mallon, National Association of Black and White Men Together
  - Youth in the Margins: A Report on the Unmet Needs of LGBT Adolescents in Foster Care, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    Lambda Legal
  - Hidden Injustice: LGBT Youth in Juvenile Courts, 2009 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Legal Services for Children
  - Assessing the HIV Prevention Needs of Gay and Bisexual Men of Color, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    U.S. Conference of Mayor
  - In the System and in the Life: A Guide for Teens and Staff to the Gay Experience in Foster Care, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Al Desetta, Youth Communication
  - Out With It: Gay and Straight Teens Write About Homosexuality, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Philip Kay, Andrea Estepa, and Al Desetta, Youth Communication
  - 2001 National School Climate Survey, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    GLSEN
  - Family, Unvalued: Discrimination, Denial, and the Fate of Binational Same-Sex Couples Under US Law, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Human Rights Watch/Immigration Equality
  - Lesbian Projects and Organizations in the United States: An Overview, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    Astraea National Lesbian Action Foundation
  - LGBTQ Grantmaking by U.S. Foundations, 2004-2008, 2012 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Funders for Lesbian and Gay Issues 2002-2004, 2006, 2012 (Tracking Report)
  - Racial Equity Campaign Benchmarks (Box 25, Folder 9)
    Funders for Lesbian and Gay Issues
  - LGBTQ Grantmakers 2008 Report Card on Racial Equity (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Out in the South: Building Resources for LGBTQ Advancement in the U.S. South (Box 25, Folder 11)
    Funders for LGBTQ Issues: Special Report, Part One
  - Special Report: The Economic Turndown and LGBTQ Grantmaking, September 2009 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Timeline of Achievements 2007-2008, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - A Global Gaze: LGBTQI Grantmaking in the South and East 2007, 2010, 2008, 2011 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Forty Years of LGBTQ Philantropy 1970-2010, January 2012 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    Funders for LGBT Issues (2 copies, one annotated)
  - The Physics of LGBTQ Funding: Momentum, Resistance and Impact, August 2013 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    Funders for LGBT Issues
  - Reaching Out: A Grantmakers' Guide to Lesbian and Gay Issues, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 17)
    Working Group on Funding Lesbian and Gay Issues
  - The Estate Project for Artists With AIDS Report, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    Alliance for the Arts
  - Queer Asian Compass: A Descriptive Directory of LGBTQ Asian American, South Asian, and Pacific Islander (AAPI) Organizations, 2009 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    National Queer API Alliance
  - Conduct Unbecoming: The 5th, 8th, 9th Annual Report on Don't Ask Don't Tell, 1999, 2002, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    SLDN
  - Survival Guide: A Comprehensive Guide to Don't Ask, Don't Tell, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Asylum Based on Sexual Orientation: A Resource Guide (1), 1996 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    IGLHRC and Lambda Legal
  - Asylum Based on Sexual Orientation: A Resource Guide (2), 1996 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Working It Out for GLB Youth (1) (Box 25, Folder 24)
    HIV Center for Clinical and Behavioral Studies, Sutherland Miller et al
  - Working It Out for GLB Youth (2) (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Asian Pacific American Same-Sex Households: A Census Report, March 22, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    Asian American Federation of NY
  - From the Declaration of Independence to the Constitution, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    ED Friedrich and McCloskey [Paul Rapoport's annotated copy]
  - Key Facts on U.S. Foundations: 2013 Edition, 2013 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    Foundation Center
  - Remembering Paul Rapoport, 2007, 2014 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    "Remembering Paul Rapoport" booklet and three copies of foundation booklet
  - Council on Foundations Evaluation Workshop, November 14-15, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    Philadelphia, PA
  - NY State Department of Health AIDS Institute Gay Men/MSM Forum, December 5-6, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    Albany, NY
  - Prescription for Change: Report on Gay Men's/MSM Health Forum, December 5-6, 2006; CD-2433 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Sexuality Research in the US: An Assessment of the Social and Behavioral Sciences, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    Executive Summary; Diane di Mauro, Ph.D., The Sexuality Research Assessment Project, The Social Science Research Council
  - Illusions of Immortality: The Confrontation of Adolescence and AIDS, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 33)
    NY State AIDS Advisory Council
  - Connections: A Resource Directory for Youth, Highlighting Services for Black and Latino Young Men and their Peers (Box 25, Folder 34)
    People of Color in Crisis
  - The Grantmaking Process: The Basics: Resources for Grantmakers, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - All Our Children: Strategies to Prevent Homelessness, Strengthen Services and Build Support for LGBTQ Youth, 2010 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    NYC Commission on LGBTQ Runaway and Homeless Youth
  - Lesbian AIDS Project Information Packet, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - The Trevor Project Survival Kit, 2007 (Box 25, Folder 38)
- Series V: DVD's and VHS
  - Absolutely Positive: "Taking Action", V-8274 (Box 26)
    Adair and Armstrong (3 Videotapes with the same title)
  - Absolutely Positive: "Taking Action", V-8275 (Box 26)
  - Absolutely Positive: "Taking Action", V-8276 (Box 26)
  - Party: A Safer Sex Videotape for Black Gay Men, V-8277 (Box 26)
    Gay Men of African Descent
  - A Place Called Home, January 25, 1995; V-8278 (Box 26)
    AIDS Resource Center
  - Toilet Training, 2004; V-8279 (Box 26)
    Sylvia Rivera Law Project
  - In the Life Episode #803, February/March 1999; V-8280 (Box 26)
  - GLSEN in the National News Television, September-November 1999; V-8281 (Box 26)
  - Pro Bono in the AIDS Epidemic, 1992; V-8282 (Box 26)
    American Bar Association: AIDS Coordination Project
  - Breaking the Silence: LGBTQ Foster Youth Tell Their Stories, September 2005; DVD-1457 (Box 26)
    NCLR
  - Breaking the Silence: LGBTQ Foster Youth Tell Their Stories - Resource CD, June 2006; CD-2432 (Box 26)
  - Before Stonewall, 1986; V-8283 (Box 26)
  - Voices from the Front, 1991; V-8284 (Box 26)
  - Dyke TV: Volume 5, 1995; V-8285 (Box 26)
  - The International Tribunal on Human Rights Violations Against Sexual Minorities, October 1995; V-8286 (Box 26)
  - Working it Out, November 1995; V-8287 (Box 26)
    HIV Center for Clinical and Behavioral Studies
  - I Just Want to Say, 1998; V-8288 (Box 26)
  - Judy Shepard PSA, V-8289 (Box 26)
  - Creating Change '98, November 12-15, 1998; TR-10588 (Box 26)
    National Gay and Lesbian Task Force -- Audio Tapes
  - Nuestra Salud: Seg. 1 "Cuidado Preventivo", 1999; V-8290 (Box 26)
    English Subtitles
  - Our House, 2000; V-8291 (Box 26)
  - That's A Family, March 2000; V-8292 (Box 26)
    Women's Educational Media
  - "Fenced Out": Courtesy video from Greenwich Village, November 2001; V-8293 (Box 26)
    Youth Council's New Neutral Zone
  - Pride for Youth Documentary, October 9, 2004; V-8294 (Box 26)
    Long Island Crisis Center
  - Pride for Youth Documentary, V-8295 (Box 26)
  - I Hear You:An AIDS/HIV Information Hotline for men and women in prison, V-8296 (Box 26)
    The AIDS in Prison Project of the Osborne Association
  - Time Indefinite -- marriage announcement, sistas lecture, Charles at home, V-8297 (Box 26)
  - The Salt Mines, V-8298 (Box 26)
    by Susana Aikin and Carlos Aparicio
Books Catalogued Separately
Eric Brandt. Dangerous Liaisons: Blacks, Gays, and the Struggle for Equality. 1999
The Center for Lesbian and Gay Studies. CLAGS Directory of Lesbian and Gay Studies. 1994/1995
Margaret Cruikshank. Lesbian Studies: Present and Future. 1982
International Gay and Lesbian Human Rights Commission, Center for Women's Global Leadership. Written Out: How Sexuality is Used to Attack Women's Organizing. 2000
Karen Hein, M.D. and Theresa Foy DiGeronimo. AIDS: Trading Fears for Facts: A Guide for Teens. 1989
Gregory L. Colvin. Fiscal Sponsorship: 6 Ways to Do it Right. 1993
The Brown Boi Project. Freeing Ourselves: A Guide to Health and Self Love for Brown Bois. 2011
el Comité Americano de Servicio de los Amigos Puentes de Respeto: Creación de Apoyo para la Juventud Lesbiana y Homosexual 1992
Youth Communication (edited by Al Desetta). The Heart Knows Something Different: Teenage Voices from the Foster Care System 1996
Edited by Martin Duberman. A Queer World: The Center for Lesbian and Gay Studies Reader 1996
Edited by Martin Duberman .Queer Representations: Reading Lives, Reading Cultures: A Center for Lesbian and Gay Studies Book 1997
Ford Foundation Sexuality and Social Change: Making the Connection: Strategies for Action and Investment 2005
Youth Communication (edited by Al Desetta) Out With It: Gay and Straight Teens Write About Homosexualty 2008
Richard Plant. The Pink Triangle: The Nazi War Against Homosexuals 1986
Masha Gessen. The Rights of Lesbians and Gay Men in the Russian Federation: An International Gay and Lesbian Human Rights Commission Report 1994
Human Rights Watch. Hatred in the Hallways: Violence and Discrimination Against Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Students in U.S. Schools 2001
Other Countries Other Countries: Black Gay Voices 1988
Youth Communication (edited by Andrea Estepa and Philip Kay). Starting with "I": Personal Essays by Teenagers 1997
Edited by Bonnie Zimmerman and Toni A.H. McNaron. The New Lesbian Studies: Into the Twenty-First Century 1996
John W. Mason for the Council on Foundations, The Foundation Center Foundation Trusteeship: Service in the Public Interest 1989
Edited by Kathleen DeBold, Gay and Lesbian Victory Fund. Out for Office: Campaigning in the Gay Nineties 1994
The Andy Warhol Photographic Legacy Program The Andy Warhol Foundation for the Visual Arts 1987-2007. includes: 20-Year Report 1987-2007, 20-Year Report 1987-2007 Grants and Exhibitions, 20-Year Report 1987-2007